{"tossups": [{"question": "While living in East Aurora, this president appointed Nathan Hall as his clerk, and he would go on to serve as this man\u2019s Postmaster General. While serving on the Ways and Means Committee, this man helped author the Black Tariff. This President finished third in the Election of 1856 while running under the Know-Nothing Party. The Fugitive Slave Act of 1850 was passed under the presidency of, for ten points, what successor to Zachary Taylor?", "answer": "Millard<b> Fillmore</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man rose to prominence as a subordinate of John Jervis at the Battle of Cape St. Vincent. This man\u2019s forces intercepted Pierre-Charles Villeneuve after they left Cadiz. This man, who lost an arm while leading an attack on Copenhagen, ordered that the message \u201cEngland expects that every man will do his duty\u201d be sent aboard his flagship, the<em> HMS Victory</em>. For ten points, name this British admiral who won the Battle of Trafalgar.", "answer": "Horatio<b> Nelson</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This non-Europe continent\u2019s \u201cCharacter\u201d was described in an 1830 work by Hegel that elucidated the idea of the \u201cAbsolute\u201d in philosophy. Jean-Paul Sartre wrote the preface to one work by an author from this country that applied Marxist principles to colonialism; that work was Frantz Fanon\u2019s<em> The Wretched</em> <em>of the Earth</em>. Edward Said [sai-eed] argued against the stereotyping of the northern part of this non-Asia continent in his<em> Orientalism</em>. For ten points, name this continent that was divided up by Europe during its namesake \u201cScramble\u201d in the late-19th century.", "answer": "<b> Africa</b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}, {}, {"question": "Frederick Douglass once said that it was easier to do this activity well \u201cthan to repair broken men.\u201dA book about this activity downplays the importance of rigid schedules and, in its seventh edition, advocated a vegetarian diet aimed at combating obesity. That book on this activity was the best-selling book in twentieth-century America after the Bible and famously begins \u201cTrust yourself. You know more than you think you do.\u201d For ten points, name this activity for which a proper method was outlined by Benjamin Spock, a pediatrician.", "answer": "<b> raising children</b> (accept<b> parenting</b>; accept \u201c<b>build strong children</b>\u201d, the exact Douglass quote; accept equivalents that relate to<b> raising babies</b> and/or<b> toddlers</b>)", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Psychology"}, {"question": "This country passed the Objectives Resolution as the basis for its constitution. It fought a nationalist movement in its eastern half with Operation Searchlight and its incursion across the Line of Control started the Kargil War. The Lahore Resolution proposed the creation of this country, which lies on the northwest side of the Radcliffe Line. For ten points, name this South Asian nation that, in 1967, officially moved its capital from Rawalpindi to Islamabad.", "answer": "Islamic Republic of<b> Pakistan</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The US Marines incorporated this game into an ad with the caption \u201cGet off the firing line [...] that\u2019s a safety violation!\u201d Norwegian Prime Minister Erna Solberg was photographed playing this game during a Parliament session. In a 2016 speech, Hillary Clinton attempted to capitalize on this game\u2019s popularity with a Get Out the Vote pun. Nintendo\u2019s stock value surged by 120 percent in the week following the release of, for ten points, what Niantic mobile game in which users may find a Pikachu while taking a walk?", "answer": "<b> Pok\u00b4emon Go</b> (prompt on Pok\u00b4emon)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "The head of this animal faces the viewer to symbolize the present in Titian\u2019s<em> Allegory of Prudence</em>. A bust of a Roman emperor wears the skin of this animal and shows him holding two golden apples and a club. This animal is frequently shown with Saint Jerome, who legendarily tamed one, and a winged version of this animal is used to symbolize the Evangelist Saint Mark. For ten points, name this animal, a Nemean one of which was killed by Hercules.", "answer": "<b> lion</b>s (accept Nemean<b> lion</b> after \u201cbust\u201d is read)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A failed hunt for this creature with an ox-head is depicted on the Altuna Runestone and the eighth Ardre stone. A god takes nine steps after slaying this creature; in another story, that god lifts the foot of this creature after it is turned into a colossus cat at Utgard. This creature is cut off of Thor\u2019s fishing line by the giant Hymir, and the releasing of its tail will start Ragnarok. For ten points, name this sibling of Hel and Fenrir, a giant snake in Norse mythology that encircles the world.", "answer": "<b> Jormungand</b>r (accept the<b> Midgard Serpent</b> or the<b> World Serpent</b>)", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {}, {"question": "This leader was captured, and hundreds of his subjects killed, in the Massacre in the Great Temple. Bernal Diaz del Castillo\u2019s<em> Historia</em> describes this man, speaking from a balcony, being stoned by his subjects while telling them to retreat from their enemy. Cuitlahuac [kweet-lah-wok] succeeded this man, whose death caused Pedro de Alvarado and hundreds of Europeans to flee the city in La Noche Triste. For ten points, name this ruler of Tenochtitlan whose reign ended with the invasion of Hern\u00b4an Cort\u00b4es\u2019conquistadors.", "answer": "<b> Moctezuma</b> II (or<b> Montezuma</b> II; accept<b> Moctezuma</b> Xocoyo)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "In the aftermath of this event, Ken Salazar claimed it was his job to \u201ckeep the boot on the neck\u201d of its perpetrator. The aftermath of this event involved extensive use of Corexit disperseants, which CEO Tony Hayward controversially claimed were used in quantities negligible in comparison to the \u201cvery big ocean.\u201dThis event, which took place at the Macondo Prospect, killed 11 people and destroyed a facility leased to BP. For ten points, name this 2010 event, an explosion and ensuing oil spill in the Gulf of Mexico.", "answer": "<b> Deepwater Horizon</b> oil spill disaster (accept<b> Macondo</b> blowout, oil spill, disaster, etc. before Macondo is said; prompt on BP (or British Petroleum) oil spill, disaster, etc. before BP is said)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "<b>One member of this family married the Marquess of Hartington while her father served as U.S. Ambassador to the U.K., then died in a 1948 plane crash. Another member of this family owned a farm in Maryland called Timberlawn, where a day camp evolved into the (+) Special Olympics, founded in honor of another member of this family who had undergone a lobotomy in 1941. Patricia and Rosemary were among the daughters of Rose, the matriarch of this family, which names (*)</b> Harvard\u2019s school of government. For ten points, name this prominent Massachusetts political family whose other members include Robert, Ted, and John.", "answer": "<b> Kennedy</b> family", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "For ten points, name this Eastern European country once ruled by Nicolae Ceau\u00b8sescu [cho-chess-koo] from Bucharest.", "answer": "<b> Romania</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>A ship of this name had its cannon, the</b><em><b> Peacemaker</b></em><b>, designed by then-captain Robert Stockton. A city of this name was briefly the site of the U.S. capital at Nassau Hall. Hugh</b> <b>Mercer died leading American forces at a battle of this name, where a (+)</b> <b>garrison under</b> <b>Charles Mawhood retreated after George Washington\u2019s assault. An explosion on board a ship of this name killed (*) </b> Abel Upshur but left sitting president John Tyler uninjured. For ten points, name this site of an American Revolutionary War victory that followed the Battle of Trenton, a New Jersey city home to a historic university.", "answer": "<b> Princeton</b> (accept Battle of<b> Princeton</b>; accept USS<b> Princeton</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>During the 2012 election campaign, this politician said that the opposing party\u2019s policies on regulation would \u201cput y\u2019all back in chains.\u201d In 2008, Christine O\u2019Donnell ran against this man for his Senate seat, which he resigned nine days into his (+) seventh term. This man\u2019s</b> <b>son served as state Attorney General and planned to run for governor until he (*)</b> died of brain cancer in May 2015. On January 12th, 2017, this man received a Presidential Medal of Freedom with Distinction from his boss. For ten points, name this father of Beau, a former Delaware Senator and Vice President of the United States under Barack Obama.", "answer": "Joe<b> Biden</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "<b>In one work, Nathan\u2019s lover tells the Brooklyn novelist Stingo about this location and how she attempted to seduce its commander. In one work, a train heads to this location as Madame Sch\u00a8achter [SHEK-tair] is beaten for claiming she sees fire. (+) Primo Levi\u2019s novel </b><em><b>If This Is A Man</b></em><b> describes his experience at this place. William Styron\u2019s novel</b><em><b> Sophie\u2019s </b><b>Choice</b></em><b> focuses on Sophie\u2019s decision to have her daughter Eva (*)</b> sent to the gas chambers at this location. Elie Wiesel\u2019s<em> Night</em> is primarily set at, for ten points, what largest Nazi concentration camp, located in Poland?", "answer": "<b> Auschwitz</b>-Birkenau (or<b> Auschwitz-Moniwitz</b>; prompt on concentration camp or Nazi death camp)", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Long Fiction"}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}